hey everybody welcome to this a1
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready
so today i'm gonna talk about
free time this is a good topic
because everyone enjoys having free time
i love having free time and you
probably do too so first
let's talk about how much free time
people have most children have
more free time than adults
when you're a kid you don't have the
responsibilities
that an adult has adults have to work
pay the bills and take care of their
children
kids usually don't have to do these
things
kids usually have to go to school
and do homework this can be difficult
but it's usually not that difficult
so children have more free time
when i was a kid i had a lot of free
time
i got home from school around 2
or 3 p.m and after that
i played a lot on weekdays
from monday to friday i probably
had around four or five hours of free
time
each day sometimes i got bored
because i had so much free time
but as i got older i had more homework
each year so each year i had
a little less free time i didn't have
too much homework though in the us
we don't get that much homework in some
other countries children have a lot of
homework
i'm glad that my school work wasn't
very hard on weekends i had
even more free time on saturday
and sunday i did many activities
weekends were the best because i had
all day to play and rest i really liked
weekends and i still do now that i'm an
adult
i don't have a lot of free time i have
to work
and do many other things i usually
start working early like at 7 00 am
or 7 30 am so
i have to wake up around 6am
when i was a kid i slept more
i usually slept for eight hours every
night
as an adult i don't sleep eight hours
every night i
usually get seven hours or seven and a
half
hours of sleep how about you
how many hours of sleep do you get
so after i finish work i have some
free time in the evening however
i usually do some extra work or
studying during this time i have to make
these youtube videos and instagram
videos
and i also study foreign languages
at night i have some free time to
just relax my wife and i
spend the evenings together and enjoy
this time
okay now let's talk about some popular
activities that people do in their free
time
for example many people like to play
sports or exercise in their free time
when i was a kid i played a lot of
sports
i played basketball baseball tennis
soccer football and golf i
really liked playing sports in my free
time
but as an adult i don't play
any sports i'm not very interested
in playing sports nowadays however
i exercise in my free time i work
out almost every day but just for a
short time
other people spend a lot of time
exercising
so another activity that people do in
their free
time is watch tv shows and movies
many people do this in their free time
i know some people who watch many hours
of tv
every day i don't watch a lot of tv
or movies i really like playing
games in my free time i play chess
online but i'm not very good
i also like playing board games with my
family
we play games like katan and
codenames do you like playing board
games
one last activity that most people do
in their free time is surf the internet
this is probably the most common
activity that people do
i spend a lot of time on the internet
some days i spend too much time on the
internet
it's not good to spend all day inside
on the computer we should try to go
outside and do other activities
too but the internet is very
entertaining so it's easy to spend
many hours surfing the web okay
now i'm gonna ask you some questions
about the video
to see if you understood write your
answers
in a comment down below number one
what time did i get home from school
when i was a kid number two how many
hours do i sleep each night number three
what game do i like playing online
alright remember to subscribe to the
channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
for more english tips and lessons i'll
see you next time
[Music]